

Batuhan Orhan

CONTACT

9

42090 Konya, Turkey



bthnorhan00@gmail.com



(+90) 5066799518



https://github.com/bthnorhan

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ bthnorhan/

Skype: bthnorhan

Whatsapp Messenger: +9050

66799518

ABOUT MF

I am an electrical and electronics engineer, but I advance my career as a software developer. I worked in various software projects and I have been actively working for about 3 years. In addition to this, I developed 10 software projects (medium and large-scale) in the team where I worked freelance. My specialities are Android (Java) and React Native. I also have front-end and back-end web programming knowledge. I took part in tasks such as developing SMS, credit card integrations and rest API. I actively use tools such as git, svn, and I frequently use various applications (such as Jira, Trello, project open) for documentation and project tracking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

07/2020 - CURRENT - Istanbul, Turkey

Software Development Team Lead - React Developer

Innovance Consultancy

- **Akbank T. A. Ş.;** I am involved in developing ATM screens with React JS.
- **T.C. Ziraat Bank;** I am involved in developing financial screens with React JS.

04/2018 - 07/2020 - Konya, Turkey

Software developer

Elfatek Electronic

 Thermometer Mobile App; Mobile-based software that communicates via BLE, which provides temperature information, adjusts and graphically displays temperature data.

Used Technologies: React-Native, React Navigation, Redux, Ble, JavaScript, JSON

• **In-house Messenger;** Web, desktop, and mobile-based software developed for use within the organization for file, information sharing, announcement, and fast communication purposes.

Used Technologies: React-native(Redux, Expo), ReactJS, Html, Css, Bootstrap, Rest API, Javascript, Json, Java.

 In-house Stock Management; Web and mobile-based software developed for the purpose of providing stock tracking and control within the organization.

Used Technologies: React-native(Redux, Expo), Rest API, Javascript, JSON.

 Password Manager Application; Mobile based software developed to ensure that passwords used within the organization are not forgotten and used for safe storage, with features such as pin protection, backup passwords, and restore from backup.

Used Technologies: Android (Java), SQLite, Realm

 Card-Based Staff Attendance System; Web and mobile-based software developed for the purpose of eliminating the forgetting of the cards and providing fast passage for the card pass systems in the institution, where the personnel can determine their identity with their company e-mail and password.

Used Technologies: Android (Java), NFC, JSON, Rest API

 Crane Simulation; Desktop-based software developed for the training of Hüma series crane controls produced by the institution, providing the movements of the model crane in the application by processing the instant data of the controller with the CAN Bus network technology.

Used Technologies: C#, Unity, CAN bus

 VR Crane and Rocket Ramp Simulation; Desktop-based software developed for the training of Hüma series crane controls and Military Control Console produced by the institution, providing the movements of the model in the application by processing the instant data of the controller with the CAN Bus network technology. Used Technologies: C#, Unity, CAN bus, Oculus Rift

 CAN Bus Analyzer Application; Desktop-based software for the can bus USB analyzer developed for the institution.

Used Technologies: C#, Winform

06/2017 - 10/2017

Volunteer Instructor

Turkcell

As a Volunteer Instructor, I gave Android training as part of the "Geleceği Yazan Kadınlar" project, which was launched in cooperation with Turkcell and TOBB Women Entrepreneurs Board. For more detailed information about the project, you can visit https://gelecegiyazanlar.turkcell.com.tr/gelecegiyazankadinlar.

PROJECTS

Other Projects

- Black Sea Fish House (React Native)
- Hexfall Replica (Unity, C#)
- Genmot GENPARA (React Native)
- Yazomi (React Native)
- Pilot Garage Mobile Sale (React Native)
- Pilot Garage (React Native)
- Brox Wedding Mobile Album (React Native)
- Konya Contactless Card Balance Application (Android NFC)
- Nil10 (React Native)
- Graduation Project (3 Dimension Object Scan)
- 2-axis Position, Time Controlled and Sun Following Solar Panel Circuit Board and Software

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2013 - 2019 - Konya, Turkey

Electrical/Electronics Engineer

Konya Technical University

2009 - 2013 - Konya, Turkey

Diploma

Konya Anatolian High School

DIGITAL SKILLS

Mobile

React Native / Java

SVN

Git / GitHub / GitLab

Web

HTML / CSS / Bootstrap / JavaScript / Php / Mysql / Codeigniter / NodeJS / Firebase / React JS / MongoDB / Socket IO

PMS

Atlassian Jira / Microsoft TFS / Trello

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

 When I worked in the R&D department, I gained project management and effective time usage skills.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS



Communication and interpersonal skills

 I gained the ability to communicate and train effectively when I was a volunteer trainer at Turkcell's "Geleceği Yazan Kadınlar" project.

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS



Management and leadership skills

 I gained the ability to managing projects, mentoring, relationship building, solving problems when I was team lead at Innovance Consultancy.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Turkish

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening Reading Spoken Spoken Writing
B2 B2 production interaction B2
B2 B2 B2

RFFFRFNCFS



References

Doç. Dr. Murat CEYLAN

Aivisiontech Founder (METU-Technopolis)

Associate Professor of Electrical and Electronics Engineering at Konya Technical University

Graduation Project Consultant

+905359230190

mceylan@ktun.edu.tr

Mehmet ACA

Turkcell, Senior Learning Solutions Specialist

+905309563161

mehmet.aca@turkcell.com.tr

Rıdvan Safa HATİPOĞLU

Elfatek Elektronik, R&D Chief

+905057027090

ridvan.safa@gmail.com

Mustafa İlker ÇAKI

Elfatek Elektronik, Senior Software Developer

+905077463031

milkercaki@gmail.com

Onur DEMİRCAN

Softtech, Software Developer

+905383077824

demircanonur06@gmail.com